[{"id": "592ead7df83302ff91e4647d", "question": "What was a Portuguese moidore?", "answer": "A gold coin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdc1758469bb8041d07a08f", "question": "What Spanish automobile manufacturer's first model was a three-wheeled two-door car?", "answer": "Kapi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab1c1fbaab681b0929219e", "question": "What car did Chevrolet design the Camaro to compete with in 1966?", "answer": "The Ford Mustang", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e6b5f9fb6c85e9e634ff46", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed \"Land of 10,000 Lakes\"?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5aab2e9358d116dab4aecb3f", "question": "Who played the inventor in the 1989 film \"Honey, I Shrunk the Kids\"?", "answer": "Rick Moranis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb54", "question": "On what mountain does Moses speak to God through the burning bush and received the Ten Commandments?", "answer": "Mt. Sinai", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c938", "question": "The koala eats the leaves from this tree?", "answer": "Eucalyptus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fb08768cf631c2414a13b57", "question": "In \"Game of Thrones\", what are the three names of Daenerys\u2019 dragons?", "answer": "Drogon, Viserion, and Rhaegal", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597de06177980686f722d189", "question": "The modern day sandwich was created during which century?", "answer": "18th Century", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae2", "question": "How many candles are on a menorah?", "answer": "9", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a288", "question": "\"Next\" and \"Paycheck\" are films based on stories by which science-fiction author?", "answer": "Philip K. Dick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a478", "question": "Lanzarote is part of which island group?", "answer": "The Canaries", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c04f", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Ecuador?", "answer": "Andean condor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2d3", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"The G.I. General\"?", "answer": "Omar Bradley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339afb", "question": "What rock musician got his stage name from the yellow and black jerseys he used to wear?", "answer": "Sting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3796ff048f679a45ab1a", "question": "In which country was the largest known T-Rex skeleton found?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9f1", "question": "What is the fear of social situations called?", "answer": "Sociophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c05e", "question": "The Winter Olympics Games were first held in which country?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af57", "question": "Which country do you associate with the Easter Rising?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597cd7cae347d002c297e4c4", "question": "What South American cities inhabitants are called \"portenos\"?", "answer": "Buenos Aires", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4b67206d333868d34d6f1", "question": "Twenty-two months of negotiation and the 1998 Good Friday Agreement ended violence in what nation?", "answer": "Northern Ireland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338889", "question": "Who turned all he touched to gold?", "answer": "King Midas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e5c", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Marge Simpson?", "answer": "Julie Kavner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdef", "question": "What's the alcohol in an Old Fashioned cocktail?", "answer": "Whiskey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4aa", "question": "The star Polaris is more commonly known by what name?", "answer": "The North Star", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e7", "question": "What is the longest one syllable word in the English language?", "answer": "Screeched", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7ce80877e98cb97778a43", "question": "Which is the highest point in the Philippines?", "answer": "Mt. Apo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59f9ba23364247bf200fb895", "question": "What Shakespearean play refers to the Eve of the Feast of Epiphany?", "answer": "Twelfth Night", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad7e910b24f84e0b9f9ffc8", "question": "What year did Botswana gain its independence from the United Kingdom?", "answer": "1966", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f01", "question": "Whose \"Adagio for Strings\" is best known as the theme from the movie \"Platoon\"?", "answer": "Samuel Barber's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e9a84ebfabb9c85d8a97c", "question": "Which mythical creature has the body of a lion, a goat's head rising from its back and a snake's head at the tip of its tail?", "answer": "Chimaera, or Chimera", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7353deec85e375820b247", "question": "Who said, \"I am prepared to meet my Maker. Whether my Maker is prepared for the ordeal of meeting me is another matter.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a835", "question": "What US state is the source of the Arkansas, Platte, and Rio Grande rivers?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b95b", "question": "What is heartsease?", "answer": "A flower", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c739", "question": "What nerves, which you need for vision, are sometimes referred to as the \"second cranial nerves\"?", "answer": "Optic nerves", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bff", "question": "What is Charlie Brown's sister's name?", "answer": "Sally", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca9d", "question": "Na is the chemical symbol for which element?", "answer": "Sodium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f1", "question": "What Agatha Christie novel was made up of two parts - England and Egypt?", "answer": "Death on the Nile", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a4a97ae61d1b4d384d5d687", "question": "What title has the wife of an Earl?", "answer": "Countess", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339240", "question": "What George Michael song was banned by the BBC and re-edited three times for MTV?", "answer": "I Want Your Sex", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff2581931a458464a93c464", "question": "What is a bonbonni\u00e8re?", "answer": "A fancy box or dish used to hold bonbons.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600399bb57a0e35c43f8389f", "question": "What German artist had Emperor Rudolph II as a patron?", "answer": "Hans von Aachen\u00a0-- He was one of the leading painters of Northern Mannerism and a painter of princely and\u00a0 aristocratic portraits.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391af", "question": "Who dramatically kissed Halle Berry on stage when he won Best Actor?", "answer": "Adrien Brody", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600241204be4723ccac22170", "question": "What Italian sculptor/architect is credited with creating the Baroque style?", "answer": "Gian Lorenzo Bernini", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339103", "question": "What year did Georges Bizet debut the opera \"Carmen\"?", "answer": "1875", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c66a", "question": "Anna's, Calliope, and Ruby-throated are species of what bird?", "answer": "Hummingbird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339225", "question": "Who plays the role of Craig the puppeteer's wife in \"Being John Malkovich\"?", "answer": "Cameron Diaz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa5b473838c5c8a417f2a", "question": "Automatonophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Ventriloquist dummies", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a2", "question": "Why is Max mad in the 1979 movie \"Mad Max\"?", "answer": "His wife and child were murdered", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d6752596a59cbdfbd3ab", "question": "What organization unveiled the largest machine on Earth in 2008?", "answer": "CERN", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf1a", "question": "What is the colour of mourning in Turkey?", "answer": "Violet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbb7", "question": "What is the largest football stadium in Brazil?", "answer": "The Maracana stadium", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cdc38e347d002c297e4e5", "question": "In which film did Madonna play a character called \"Gloria Tatlock\"?", "answer": "Shanghai Surprise", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c51", "question": "Who starred in the lead male role in the 1968 movie \"Planet of the Apes\"?", "answer": "Charlton Heston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adbc", "question": "Which country was split into zones by the 'Yalta Agreement'?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e1f", "question": "What artist sold only one painting, \"The Red Vineyard\", during his lifetime?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaad", "question": "Autodromo Nazionale Monza is located in which country?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b8cf2f94b094db915830ae", "question": "The Bical grape originates from which European country?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8c7", "question": "The point on land closest to the North Pole belongs to what nation?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339146", "question": "Who created the character Pinocchio?", "answer": "Carlo Collodi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388eb", "question": "What is the dot in the \"i\" called?", "answer": "A tittle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b271", "question": "What did \"Glamorous Glennis\" do on October 19, 1947?", "answer": "Broke the sound barrier for the first time", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb5f", "question": "What coastal Atlantic US state has \"The Shag\" as their official state dance?", "answer": "South Carolina", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339839", "question": "Who won a Grammy Award for his album \"52nd Street\"?", "answer": "Billy Joel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c6", "question": "In which English county is Charnwood Forest located?", "answer": "Leicestershire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a45f", "question": "The \"Carnac Stones\" are located what country?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399b1", "question": "What was Aerosmith\u2019s first Top 10 song on the Billboard charts?", "answer": "Dream On", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b8cc5494b094db9158309e", "question": "What was the name of the protagonist in the 2016 film \u201cZootopia\u201d?", "answer": "Judy Hopps", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339651", "question": "What kind of animal is the title character in the 1998 movie \"Paulie\"?", "answer": "Parrot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdabdf30b8cce1e6fda7065", "question": "Which wine is released annually on the third Thursday in November?", "answer": "Beaujolais Nouveau", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339190", "question": "What are Tom and Jerry?", "answer": "A Cat and a Mouse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c933", "question": "What is the correct name for a baby mink?", "answer": "Kit or Kitten", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aca9", "question": "Which exiled South Asian leader returned home in 2007, only to be assassinated two months later?", "answer": "Benazir Bhutto", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339507", "question": "Who provides the voice for Abe Sapien in the 2004 movie \"Hellboy\"?", "answer": "David Hyde Pierce", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339096", "question": "Who were the siblings of the Greek god Hera?", "answer": "Poseidon, Zeus, Hades, Demeter, Hestia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389c3", "question": "What kinds of creatures were Flopsy and Mopsy in the first book by Beatrix Potter?", "answer": "Rabbits", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f00601dd7bf43be5e7f9", "question": "In diner slang, what's a 50-50?", "answer": "Coffee with half and half", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339457", "question": "How many cars does Memphis have to steal to save his brother in \"Gone In 60 Seconds\"?", "answer": "50", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c9b", "question": "What John Steinbeck novel gets its title from a lyric in \"The Battle Hymn of the Republic\"?", "answer": "The Grapes of Wrath", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60173d3644491cbd7c5a17ab", "question": "What was the original name for the Grammy Award(s)? ", "answer": "Gramophone Award ", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600243224be4723ccac22191", "question": "Charles Marlow is the narrator of which Joseph Conrad novella?", "answer": "\"Heart of Darkness\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2cfa22596a59cbdfbd371", "question": "Who said, \"Do I not destroy my enemies when I make them my friends\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f5", "question": "In what U.S. City was the Rag\u00fa brand of Italian-style sauces first produced?", "answer": "Rochester, New York", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c9f7eeb4e2c7fbd389674d", "question": "What year was Strongbow cider introduced to the market?", "answer": "1962", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3ecf58b5801b8f54a7faf", "question": "Peleus and Thetis were the parents of what famed warrior?", "answer": "Achilles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae96", "question": "The 16th Constitutional Amendment, enacted in 1913 allowed the US federal government to do what?", "answer": "Tax personal income", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7663beec85e375820b27c", "question": "Which famous mountain peak is not part of a mountain range?", "answer": "Mt. Kilimanjaro", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b073", "question": "Who was the first Secretary of the Treasury of the United States?", "answer": "Alexander Hamilton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58bb33a5e368446ca7bd6847", "question": "In \"The Wizard of Oz\", what was the lion in search of?", "answer": "Courage", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338932", "question": "What is the given name of the famous German composer and pianist Beethoven?", "answer": "Ludwig", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a230", "question": "Who played the title role in the film \"Mad Max Beyond Thunderdome\"?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2c8", "question": "Over its 7 season run, how many episodes of the TV show \"30 Rock\" were aired?", "answer": "138", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afdf", "question": "In the year 1900, what killed over 8,000 people in Galveston, Texas?", "answer": "Hurricane", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f65", "question": "Gene Kelly sings \"Singin' in the Rain\" over the end credits of what 1971 movie?", "answer": "A Clockwork Orange", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e0", "question": "Who wrote the first three books of the \"Millennium\" novel series?", "answer": "Stieg Larsson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ea", "question": "Which is the second largest US state in surface area?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601219ec63c99d48cd169afd", "question": "Who is the oldest man to win People Magazine\u2019s sexiest man alive?", "answer": "Sean Connery", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f9f4a3aaf848b908361b87b", "question": "What is the name of the tall white hat chefs wear?", "answer": "A Toque", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f1e", "question": "What author created the land of Fantastica?", "answer": "Michael Ende", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fde493ac6c6b019850c9a6d", "question": "Which Old Testament prophet said \"Thou art the man\"?", "answer": "Nathan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f20", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Rosemary Murphy and Jennifer Jason Leigh?", "answer": "Dorothy Parker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeb0", "question": "Which American female flyer disappeared without a trace over the Pacific in 1937?", "answer": "Amelia Earhart", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce5", "question": "What is Mr. Belvedere's given name?", "answer": "Lynn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2b9", "question": "Who created the TV show \"30 Rock\"?", "answer": "Tina Fey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c9e", "question": "What Ray Charles song was the basis for Kanye West's \"Gold Digger\"?", "answer": "I Got a Woman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b17466cbb2d29f81593b707", "question": "Which TV detective series is set in the town of Denton?", "answer": "A Touch of Frost", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a975661d1b4d384d5d683", "question": "Where would you find a \"crossbuck\"?", "answer": "At a railroad crossing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339faf", "question": "Green Lantern's ring is powerless against objects of what color?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b7ffae63a3a814d89068c5f", "question": "What was the number of Intel's first commercially available microprocessor?", "answer": "4004", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339681", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Homer's middle name?", "answer": "Jay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af67", "question": "Before being hanged, whose last words were \"I only regret that I have but one life to lose for my country\"?", "answer": "Nathan Hale", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b22", "question": "When it debuted, what FOX series was promoted as a \"weekly nationwide criminal manhunt\"?", "answer": "America's Most Wanted", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a7f5876f5f79087132fb3e", "question": "Which religious figure is depicted in many of the tallest statues on Earth?", "answer": "Buddha", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab5e", "question": "What is the capital of the Czech Republic?", "answer": "Prague", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133956e", "question": "What year was Robert Liberman's, All I Want for Christmas released?", "answer": "1991", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0df", "question": "In what year was the \"Star Spangled Banner\" designated the US National Anthem?", "answer": "1931", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600f753da9e54d890926f707", "question": "How long is New Zealand\u2019s Ninety Mile Beach?", "answer": "55 miles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ded09aea2747c8aff16d2a", "question": "What is extracted from the ore cassiterite?", "answer": "Tin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe77619eec85e375820b316", "question": "What waterway divides Turkey between Europe and Asia?", "answer": "Bosporus Strait", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5971df3a89261e916c8e09a7", "question": "How is the groundnut better known?", "answer": "The peanut", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a272", "question": "Who played the character of Corie Bratter in the 1967 film \"Barefoot in the Park\"?", "answer": "Jane Fonda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59049f03cf93664eb10486b7", "question": "What US state is home to the \"One Shell Square\" skyscraper?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2dd", "question": "What civilization worshiped a feathered serpent called Quetzalcoatl?", "answer": "The Aztecs", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c250", "question": "What do you call an animal that eats both plants and animals?", "answer": "An Omnivore", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389d8", "question": "What Jane Austen book has many parallels with \"Bridget Jones's Diary\" including the main male character?", "answer": "Pride and Prejudice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c332", "question": "What was the purpose of the ancient medicinal confection made from the marshmallow plant?", "answer": "To treat irritated mucous membranes and increase the flow of breast milk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff66dfe52a821ff76ae8b19", "question": "What philosophical tradition is associated with Jean-Paul Sartre?", "answer": "Existentialism", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f28401dd7bf43be5e80f", "question": "What is the whiskey that evaporates from its barrel called?", "answer": "Angel's share", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be8e", "question": "What is the American term for the rope maneuver called \"abseiling\" in Europe?", "answer": "Rappeling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008fdfcf842fa4c4ba96c1", "question": "What century did John Milton write the epic poem \"Paradise Lost\"?", "answer": "17th Century", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad7ea81b24f84e0b9f9ffd5", "question": "Homichlophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Fog or humidity", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d1184b4fea7fe947a22283", "question": "What is the correct name for brown coal?", "answer": "Lignite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c49", "question": "What is Lady Gaga's full name?", "answer": "Stefani Joanne Angelina Germanotta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590498b2cf93664eb104868a", "question": "A statue of Lady Godiva stands in the centre which English city?", "answer": "Coventry", "category": "art"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a88a", "question": "What historic plaza is named for the first publisher of the \"Dallas Morning News\"?", "answer": "Dealey Plaza", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395e8", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Principal Charming,\" who does Skinner fall in love with?", "answer": "Patty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b326", "question": "Who was the wife of King Ahab?", "answer": "Jezebel of Sidon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6d8", "question": "What element combines with sodium to make ordinary table salt?", "answer": "Chlorine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ad", "question": "What does the \"PJ\" stand for in the name PJ Harvey?", "answer": "Polly Jean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4bc649076251badbeac8", "question": "What was U.S. President Woodrow Wilson's reelection campaign slogan in 1916?", "answer": "\"He Kept Us Out of War\" -- Despite the slogan, he asked Congress to declare war in 1917.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b80", "question": "Who wrote \"Analogy of the Cave\"?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015ef03fe83fe1f2a824c0c", "question": "In what year did Christmas become a federal holiday in the United States?", "answer": "1870", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d9b", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"The American President\"?", "answer": "Michael Douglas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa52a7c73aa70ea0b70b1c", "question": "Frankenmuth, a U.S. city nicknamed \"Little Bavaria\", is located in what state?", "answer": "Michigan (It is a German-style town in Saginaw County. It is well known for its hotels and old-style German buildings.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad49", "question": "In 1978, what terrorist group kidnapped and murdered former Italian prime minister Aldo Moro?", "answer": "Red Brigade", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a940", "question": "What river's waterfalls led to the naming of the Cascade Range?", "answer": "The Columbia's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c63a", "question": "Which bird lays the largest eggs?", "answer": "Ostrich", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396f5", "question": "Where does Yogi Bear live?", "answer": "Jellystone National Park", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133998b", "question": "What was the name of the main police detective played by Jack Webb on the TV show \"Dragnet\"?", "answer": "Joe Friday", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5cd", "question": "Buzzards Bay separates mainland Massachusetts from what land mass?", "answer": "Cape Cod", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339220", "question": "Who were the principal members of the band \"The Beatles\"?", "answer": "John Lennon, Paul McCartney, George Harrison, Ringo Starr", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c12e", "question": "Boxer Jersey Joe Walcott was better known as who?", "answer": "Arnold Raymond Cream", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b61", "question": "What Paul Newman film spawned the hit song \"Raindrops Keep Fallin' on My Head\"?", "answer": "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c314", "question": "What irrational mathematical constant is known as the golden ratio?", "answer": "1.6180339887", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c3e1877e98cb97778998", "question": "What is the lowest elevation river in the world?", "answer": "Jordan River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe12d0de39efa6330e0fec9", "question": "How long is the Panama Canal?", "answer": "51 miles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aff", "question": "Which character killed Jay Gatsby?", "answer": "George Wilson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0b4", "question": "In 1992, which US state began offering tourist info at 1-800-33-GUMBO?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c8a55e90aac110e4167073", "question": "To make beer, what is barley normally made into?", "answer": "Malt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7b3", "question": "Edam cheese originated in which country?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f30576d5aa2bc17b61b2ad0", "question": "What is the historical term, \"Dipsomania\" another name for what modern day condition?", "answer": "Alcholism", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b002", "question": "Who was the primary author of the Declaration of Independence?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc1d", "question": "What designer invented the Rubik's cube?", "answer": "Erno Rubik", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133965b", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of the Springfield Elementary lunchlady?", "answer": "Doris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fde4e82c6c6b019850c9a84", "question": "November 11, 1921 marked the first anonymous burial at what famous U.S. cemetery?", "answer": "Arlington National Cemetery", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd7b", "question": "What kind of wine takes its name from the Spanish town of Jerez, where it is made?", "answer": "Sherry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b174691bb2d29f81593b708", "question": "What were the name of the two space shuttles in the 1998 film \"Armageddon\"?", "answer": "Freedom and Independence", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede6216ce05a3942286df6", "question": "Who is the host of the Travel Channel's culinary adventure show \"No Reservations\"?", "answer": "Anthony Bourdain", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3e8", "question": "When did the Republic of South Sudan gain its independence?", "answer": "July 9, 2011", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133912f", "question": "Dr. Hans Zarkov is a character from which classic American comic strip?", "answer": "Flash Gordon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9f1", "question": "In which Mediterranean Sea are the Cyclades islands?", "answer": "The Aegean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600cc46f6de0eb824d4052f3", "question": "Which African country was formerly known as Abyssinia?", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395e4", "question": "In The Simpsons, who said: \"Hello, beautiful. No ring, I see. So you are only arranged to be married.\"?", "answer": "Apu Nahasapeemapetilon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f98", "question": "What character from a pop song wears electric boots and a mohair suit?", "answer": "Bennie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7fa", "question": "At which university was the beverage Gatorade developed?", "answer": "University of Florida", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb40", "question": "What color is the 4-ball in a game of pool?", "answer": "Purple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a659", "question": "Which eastern US state is home to the Kittatinny Mountains?", "answer": "New Jersey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c47d", "question": "What is the Gulf Stream?", "answer": "Warm ocean current in the Atlantic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cad7", "question": "Hydrargyrum is an old name for which element on the periodic table?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5909caddbb53d1af658864d3", "question": "What ABC Original Movie, starring Jenny McCarthy, air on December 10, 2006?", "answer": "Santa Baby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc8420078d18506ae1fe489", "question": "What species is the tallest tree in the world?", "answer": "California Redwood", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff66bb752a821ff76ae8b0f", "question": "What was the first country to institute an eight-hour workday?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397e8", "question": "Which boat\u00a0passed through the Sea of\u00a0Green, the Sea of Holes and\u00a0the Sea of Time?", "answer": "The Yellow Submarine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c33", "question": "Gilbert Stuart is best known for his work in what genre of painting?", "answer": "Portraits", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f32", "question": "Which band member of Mother Love Bone died of drug overdose?", "answer": "Andrew Wood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76712eec85e375820b28f", "question": "Into which body of water does the Yukon River discharge?", "answer": "Bering Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b112", "question": "What state did Gerald Ford represent in Congress before being promoted to Richard Nixon's Vice-President?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921a", "question": "What female singer is discussed at the start of the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b6d", "question": "Who won a Best Supporting Actor Oscar for the 2004 movie \"Million Dollar Baby\"?", "answer": "Morgan Freeman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398ce", "question": "Whose first hit single was the song, \"Bye Bye Love\"?", "answer": "The Everly Brothers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff20f0c31a458464a93c42d", "question": "What is the name of the fishing boat that is featured in the book \"The Perfect Storm\"?", "answer": "The Andrea Gail", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4cd", "question": "What was the first man-made object to leave the Solar System?", "answer": "Voyager 1", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e9b6fe83fe1f2a824beb", "question": "Queen Mary Tudor of England is better known to history by what name?", "answer": "Bloody Mary", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2cb", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"The Little Corporal\"?", "answer": "Napoleon Bonaparte", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393f3", "question": "Who directed the 1997 movie \"The Fifth Element\"?", "answer": "Luc Besson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad2e", "question": "Captain James Cook discovered what country in 1769 and claimed it for Great Britain?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f9f4c58af848b908361b87f", "question": "What company did the founders of YouTube work for before starting YouTube?", "answer": "PayPal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fc2f4a5cee580c7f8fd1e59", "question": "What was the name of the commission that investigated the assassination of John F. Kennedy?", "answer": "Warren Commission", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a722", "question": "What cave found in New Mexico, is the deepest cave in the continental US?", "answer": "Lechuguilla Cave", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fedd8976ce05a3942286d71", "question": "What is the required amount of years a player must be out of high school before being eligible to play in the NFL?", "answer": "Three years", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab83", "question": "What year did Sierra Leone gain its independence from the UK?", "answer": "1961", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5909d128bb53d1af65886500", "question": "In the movie \"The Nightmare Before Christmas\", who wants to take over Christmas and orders the kidnapping of Santa Claus?", "answer": "Jack Skellington", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea8386ff048f679a45ac28", "question": "What is the minimum speed for a Category 5 hurricane?", "answer": "157 mph", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbee", "question": "What popular designer was hired by Hermes as creative director in 2003?", "answer": "Jean Paul Gaultier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5d8", "question": "In the computer world, does the abbreviation DOS stand for?", "answer": "Disk Operating System", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe0df12fcbed638185eaa18", "question": "What is the largest ski area in the world?", "answer": "Les Trois Vall\u00e9es, France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f2e", "question": "Who wrote \"Il Milione\" while in prison?", "answer": "Marco Polo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f164bb2f9b80650dbe7f92d", "question": "Which Marvel Cinematic Universe character was frozen in ice for 66 years?", "answer": "Captain America", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe655aaae7e414034b5aeb7", "question": "Which ancient wonder was burned down by a fame-seeking arsonist?", "answer": "Temple of Artemis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b265", "question": "Who did the American media nickname \"Muttnik\"?", "answer": "Laika", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef659b6ce05a3942286e6f", "question": "Who was the first actress to wear pants to the Oscars?", "answer": "Barbara Streisand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339759", "question": "Who directed Out Of Sight?", "answer": "Steven Soderbergh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a415", "question": "What US city is home to the annual \"All-American Soap Box Derby\"?", "answer": "Akron, Ohio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b6b1e662d71a5365100c", "question": "What is the name of the vampire hunter and animator in Laurell K. Hamilton's \"The Harlequin\"?", "answer": "Anita Blake", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7f7", "question": "On what continent is the Balkan Peninsula?", "answer": "Europe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c316", "question": "What is one of pi's rational approximations?", "answer": "22/7", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4e1a506d333868d34d729", "question": "Which country did England send convicts to between 1788 and 1868?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a917", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Ticonderoga?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe69fc820565ad31a57c790", "question": "Where did the \u201cwiki\u201d in Wikipedia come from?", "answer": "Hawaiian for \"fast\" or \"quick\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7b9", "question": "What is measured in Watts?", "answer": "Power", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd18b1329d03ab85b632b2e", "question": "Who said, \"Two things are infinite: the universe and human stupidity, and I'm not sure about the universe\"?", "answer": "Einstein", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c759", "question": "What human organs are affected by glaucoma?", "answer": "The eyes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b44c", "question": "In 1994, which Scandinavian country voted to stay out of the European Union?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d0562596a59cbdfbd37a", "question": "Who said By all means marry. If you get a good wife you will become happy, and if you get a bad one you will become a philosopher?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c350", "question": "What object is theorized to lie at the center of the Milky Way?", "answer": "A black hole", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6014c47efbde8045e484669c", "question": "What are the only large cats that roar together as a group?", "answer": "Lions -- Used to mark territories, a pride of lions can be heard from 5 miles away.  Even the young cubs will join in the roaring.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b92a", "question": "What nationality was Dr. James Naismith, the inventor of basketball?", "answer": "Canadian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bc1d99ed702eaa27a66982a", "question": "Which Swedish musician sang the song \"Save Tonight\"?", "answer": "Eagle-Eye Cherry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ea", "question": "Who is the creator of Perry Mason?", "answer": "Erle Stanley Gardner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c8f9fbde8045e48466e5", "question": "After dogs, what is thought to be the first domesticated farm animal?", "answer": "Goats were the first farm animal to be domesticated according to many historians.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c34", "question": "What year were the first Grammy Awards awarded?", "answer": "1959", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b75a", "question": "What is the name of the baby depicted on the Sacagawea dollar coin?", "answer": "Pomp", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a18c", "question": "Who was the first woman to win an Oscar Best Actress in 1929?", "answer": "Janet Gaynor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afef", "question": "President William McKinley was a member of what political party?", "answer": "Republican Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea4041ff048f679a45ab67", "question": "What is an urolith?", "answer": "A bladder stone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd66a49a5bfecdd737e0882", "question": "What was Nike's original name?", "answer": "Blue Ribbon Sports", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d4d", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"Caged\"?", "answer": "Eleanor Parker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6002435d4be4723ccac22195", "question": "In William Shakespeare\u2019s \"A Midsummer Night\u2019s Dream\", what is the name of the King of the Fairies?", "answer": "Oberon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7f0", "question": "What city, located at the head of the Niagara River, is the seat of New York's Erie County?", "answer": "Buffalo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60173fdc44491cbd7c5a17b7", "question": "John the Baptist's father was who?", "answer": "The father of John the Baptist was Zechariah.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c953", "question": "What is the meaning of the name of the constellation Draco?", "answer": "Dragon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a4d964a08b8581f80b092a6", "question": "How old did Canada turn on July 1, 2017?", "answer": "150 years old", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59a1a29312f2a7826b9b871d", "question": "What was the name of the first synthetic plastic ever developed?", "answer": "Bakelite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd66377a5bfecdd737e0850", "question": "How long have dogs been domesticated?", "answer": "15,000 years", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6007820ebd51d85e222ab652", "question": "What object commonly appears in Picasso's paintings?", "answer": "Guitars (Although his Cubist works approach abstraction, he never relinquished the objects of the real world as subject matter.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df3", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"trek\"?", "answer": "Afrikaans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe36d7d0ada16518afdc042", "question": "What does \"UL\" in a circle mean, when found on electrical equipment?", "answer": "Underwriters Laboratory", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c4", "question": "Tin cans were invented in 1810, but is it true that can openers did not appear until 50 years later?", "answer": "Yes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe3f03b8b5801b8f54a7fb9", "question": "Which building became the world's tallest when it opened in 1973?", "answer": "Sears Tower (formerly)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a436", "question": "Is Japan closer to the North Pole or the South Pole?", "answer": "North Pole", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393bf", "question": "On what island was Jurassic Park located?", "answer": "Isla Nublar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fd7", "question": "Who wrote the book \"A Brief History of Time'' In 1988?\u00a0", "answer": "Stephen Hawking\u00a0", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c77f877e98cb977789cf", "question": "Why is the Bronx called the Bronx?", "answer": "After a landowner named Jonas Bronck", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c924", "question": "What are a group of magpies called?", "answer": "A tittering", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ade3", "question": "What was Liu Bang, founder of the Han Dynasty, posthumously known as?", "answer": "Emperor Gaozu of Han", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b685e662d71a53651009", "question": "What French ballet term means \"in front\"?", "answer": "Devant", "category": "arts"}]